♪ Oh, Mr. Tailor ♪
["Mr. Tailor" playing]
- ♪ Fix it ♪
- ♪ Oh, Mr. Tailor ♪
♪ Holding the scissors ♪
♪ One cut, and it's settled ♪
[Ibyang] Aunt Audrey?
[gasps]
[Ibyang] Your lips look red.
And Aunt Audrey's lipstick is fading.
Come on!
Let's eat. Come on.
[Noel] My buddy thinks
Delfin stole you from me!
It's true, isn't it?!
How many times did you do it, huh?!
- [Cita] You're hurting me.
- [Noel] How many times?!
Did something happen
between you and Aunt Audrey?
[in English] Anyway,
it's-- It's complicated.
[in English] It's complicated.
[Red] I'm still not comfortable
with that Atoy.
Audrey shouldn't have agreed
to co-parent with him.
We can't do anything about it, hon.
[Red] What if they get back together?
What if they get married?
If those two end up together,
it's like letting a snake into this house.
Is there a man with you inside the room?
None, Dad.
[in English] Uh,
I'll call you back later. Okay? Bye!
You can't sit here. Find another table.
[chair scraping, utensils shattering]
A girl pulled her seat,
that's why she fell.
[Janine] What's that?
[Ibyang] This really belongs
to Sister Tonet.
I just borrowed it,
so I can always be with her.
[Audrey] Janine is still upset with you.
I don't know how we'll tell her.
PREVIOUSLY
[suave music playing]
- [thuds softly]
- [groans]
Ouchy.
[hissing]
[screams]
[staff] There!
So, you're here.
Ma'am, are you ready for fishing?
Uh, wait a moment.
Let's wait for the kids first.
Ah, okay.
- They're taking too long.
- Yes, they are.
Ma'am, sir, the girl with you, Ibyang…
She's at the lobby drinking water.
She said she got lost
in the forest earlier.
- [Audrey] What?
- Forest?
What about Janine?
What about her companion, the other girl?
She said Janine took her
to the tall grass area,
then left her there.
She doesn't know
where her companion is now.
Oh, no! Why did they go there?
There are monitor lizards
and snakes there.
- Especially now, it's summer.
- My God.
- Please come with us there.
- [Atoy] Let's go, let's go.
- Ah, let's find Janine.
- [indistinct]
- Come on, Atoy!
- [Atoy] Where?
[suave theme music playing]
[motorcycle revving]
[sewing machine whirring]
[snipping]
[sewing machine clacking]
- [gun cocks]
- [gunfire]
[gunfire]
[clicking]
[snipping]
[music swells]
[electronic blipping]
[Cita] Karla.
[sighs]
Just be patient with your father, okay.
Next time, I'll set aside food for you.
It's fine, Mom. I'm okay here.
Even if the food at home is delicious,
it tastes bad when you eat
with someone negative.
Maybe your father just woke up
on the wrong side of the bed.
Where's Ame?
She bought something outside.
[sighs]
[suspicious music playing]
Mom, what's this?
Ah-- Dirt. Maybe I walked
through some dirt earlier.
That's a bruise, isn't it?
Where did you get this?
You never got that before.
Dad?
[tense music playing]
Karla!
- Karla!
- [Audrey] Janine!
- [Audrey] Oh my God!
- [Atoy] Janine!
- [Audrey] Ja-Janine, my dear!
- [Atoy] Janine.
[Audrey gasping]
[staff] Wait, wait.
[ominous music playing]
[gasps] My child!
[Atoy] Her heartbeat is fast, and there's…
- [Audrey gasping]
- [Atoy, in English] Snakebite.
She was bitten by a snake.
Oh, no! Oh, child!
[music swells]
Help us. Help her!
[Atoy] Let's go.
[Audrey] Janine, my child!
Dad! Dad!
Karla, don't fight
with your father anymore.
Admit it to me first.
Did he hurt you?
Here, look!
What's this?
It's my fault.
We fought. I disrespected him.
That's normal for married couples.
Mom, it's normal to fight.
But it's not normal for him to hurt you,
especially when you're fighting.
Especially since you're his wife!
[pensive music playing]
It won't happen again.
Mom, you don't know that!
Mom, it's 2026.
You don't have to put up with that man.
It's obvious you don't love him,
and he hurts you.
He's a drunkard and a gambler.
Mom, he has no redeeming qualities.
Kick him out.
Karla, he's still your father.
Mom, I always hear that.
That mindset is toxic.
Just because he's my father doesn't mean
he automatically has immunity
from all his sins.
No way.
It's my fault anyway.
Karla, don't you love your father anymore?
Mom, I have no choice but to love him.
I grew up knowing he was my father.
But he was never a dad to me.
Mom, he's not a loss in my life.
[Cita sniffles]
So, if you can't kick him out,
I will.
[rousing music playing]
[doctor] Good thing the snake
was non-venomous.
We already administered
an anti-tetanus booster for the snakebite.
She had symptoms of heatstroke,
which is why she was found unconscious.
She already has an ice pack
and IV fluids for hydration.
We continue to monitor the patient,
but most likely, your child
will be discharged tonight.
[Audrey] Thank you.
[in English] Thank you, Doc.
[Atoy] Oh.
Your daughter is okay now.
Um…
Good thing we found her right away.
Because otherwise,
her other organs might have shut down
because of the heatstroke.
What if the snake had been venomous?
Why are you thinking that?
It wasn't venomous, come on.
I shouldn't have left her with Ibyang.
Oh?
Wait.
Wait. Are you saying
this is Ibyang's fault?
I know it's not her fault.
But it's true.
This wouldn't have happened
to our daughter
if Ibyang wasn't there!
I know Ibyang.
She's not a bad kid.
She wouldn't do that.
So, what are you saying?
That our daughter is bad?
What kind of father are you to think that?
[in English] Janine may not
be perfect, Atoy.
But maybe you're forgetting
she's your child.
[rousing music playing]
Janine, my child.
[Janine] I accompanied her
to the restroom,
but she said she wanted to go somewhere,
beyond the fence.
We went because she said
there was a beautiful view there.
Then, when I looked back,
she suddenly disappeared.
[pensive music playing]
She deliberately made me get lost.
Was that really her intention?
Janine, think carefully.
[pensive music playing]
Is that really what happened?
[Janine] Yes, Daddy.
Don't you believe me?
[suspicious music playing]
Did Ibyang tell you another story,
that's why
you believe her instead?
Is that it, huh?
[sniffles]
Why-- Why do you always side with her?
You know, I feel like
I'm not your child because…
it seems you love Ibyang more than me.
Janine, don't say that. That's not true.
Of course, we love you both.
- Ah, let's--
- Ah, Atoy, can we talk outside?
[pensive music playing]
- [Siony] There are no women's clothes.
- [Karla] Ten pesos, one garment!
- Oh, just ten!-
- [indistinct]
- I'll take some
- Just ten pesos,
- for my nephew.
- one garment!
This suits you, yes.
- [woman] Oh, here, shoes!
- [indistinct]
- That fits you, yes.
- This too, it looks good on you.
- Oh, right, Mom! That's fine, oh!
- [Karla] Yes, only ten pesos.
- Oh, this.
- [Noel] Hey, hey!
- [indistinct]
Hey, move!
[ominous music playing]
These are mine! These are my clothes!
They're not for sale!
- We already paid for some of them.
- You'll regret this, Karla!
Don't worry!
Everything I sell here,
I'll give to you, so you can leave!
You're kicking me out, you rude child?!
You're not?!
My mother is so kind to you.
She served you more than me,
and you still hurt her!
My mother will not be
a battered wife as long as I live.
So, get out!
Oh, Noel!
You're beating up Cita?!
[gasps] You're so cruel!
You're such a bad person!
- Yes! That's forbidden, right?
- [clamoring]
- [tense music playing]
You're all gossipmongers!
Get out!
- Out! So early--
- Your clothes are ugly anyway!
You're uglier!
- [cackles]
- [clamoring]
Get out! You're all ugly!
[Siony] Stop drinking!
You're ruining the day!
Out!
- We're right here!
- Out!
- We're right here, Karla!
- You can't enter our house!
This is my home!
- [grunts]
- Noel, Noel!
- No way!
- [Noel] What?!
I'm just making sure
she's telling the truth.
Maybe you're forgetting
that this child has a tendency to lie.
What?
Janine already cried to you,
and that's what you're thinking?!
Listen first.
At the restaurant,
didn't Ibyang fall from the chair?
Oh, I talked to a kid.
She said Janine really pulled
the chair, that's why Ibyang fell.
Oh? I didn't tell you, so there wouldn't
be trouble because I don't want trouble.
- I want us to enjoy.
- [in English] You know what? Okay, fine.
So, Ibyang fell from the chair.
Maybe she already suffered for it,
since our daughter was bitten
by a snake and had heatstroke!
Suffered?
[in English] Oh, wait.
I'm not happy about what happened, okay.
What I'm saying is, I don't want
this child to get used to lying.
She always makes up stories.
Poor Ibyang!
[pensive music playing]
Our daughter deserves pity too.
[nurse] Ma'am, your child is calling you.
- [sinister music playing]
- [phone ringing]
- Hello?
- [Gemma] Hello, Sir Atoy?
Ibyang and I are here at the hospital.
She wants to see Janine.
Yes, okay. I'll go out
to the hallway near the ER.
Let's meet there.
You're unbelievable, Cita!
Why did you let your child
put my things outside?!
If you want me to leave, you say it to me!
Don't yell at my mother!
Karla, don't butt in, okay!
- This is between me and my wife!
- Karla, Karla!
Let me and your father talk first.
- Go on.
- No, Mom.
I won't leave you
to your worthless husband!
Repeat what you said!
You're worthless!
I wish you weren't the one my mom married!
I'm okay with not being able
to live in this world,
as long as you aren't
my mom's husband and she's happy!
You imbecile!
- Hey! Stop it! You know…
- What's the matter with you?!
- You're so ungrateful!
- [Karla grunts]
- Let her go!
- You're so ungrateful!
Both of you should leave!
- [Noel] You leave!
- [Cita] Let her go!
- I'll take my mother with me!
- [clamoring]
[Karla] Mom!
[grunts]
[thuds, then clinks]
Karla, stop!
Karla, stop.
[Cita cries] Stop, stop.
[ominous music playing]
- [grunts]
- [screams]
[foreboding music playing]
- [Noel] Get out of there!
- [Karla] Drop that!
I'll kill her!
[wails]
Mom.
[sobs] You're truly an animal.
[sobbing] I'll kill you first
before you kill my child.
[tense music playing]
[sobs] I put up with you.
I took all the insults you threw at me
and your resentment toward me.
But for you to involve my child?
[sobs] I won't allow it.
[sobs] We're done.
Leave!
Cita.
[thumps softly]
Maybe you forgot!
I saved you from shame!
You should be thankful
because I accepted your child,
even though she's not mine!
[rousing music playing]
What?!
[sobbing]
Mom…
What is he saying?
Say that again. I'm not your daughter?
What, Cita?
Tell her the truth!
So, she'll be embarrassed
for trying to kick me out!
[sobs]
I'm the one kicking you out-- [sobs]
I don't want you anymore.
[sobs]
Because I hurt you, huh?!
[pensive music playing]
That's just right
because you cheated on me!
You cheated on me!
Mom, what is he saying?
[sobbing]
Cita, don't cry your way out of this!
Tell the truth!
I'm not the only bad spouse here.
You are too!
Right?!
Why don't you tell her the truth?!
You can't, because it's shameful?!
Because you're so ashamed?!
Mom, tell me now, Mom.
[sobbing]
Who is my father, Mom?
It's Delfin!
Delfin is your father!
Atoy is your brother!
- [tense music playing]
- [sobbing]
Mom, is that true?
She won't admit it to you!
Because her image will be ruined!
But your mother cheated on me!
She's promiscuous!
Stop it!
All right now! Yes!
[sobs] I made a mistake then!
[sobs] But I don't want this anymore.
I can't accept you anymore.
I don't want you.
Get out of here!
- Leave!
- [Karla] Mom!
- You leave! You!
- That's enough!
Even if she wronged you,
you have no right to hurt her!
[sobs]
Enough. Noel, that's enough.
That's enough.
[sobbing]
Karla, that's enough.
[in English] So, is Miss Cita
in danger right now?
[in English] I mean, if her husband
is punching her, right?
[in English] I think so! Cannot be!
- [in English] Uh, the situation here is--
- [boy] Brother Nestor!
- Oh, oh?
- Oh?
[in English] Soft drinks, soft drinks,
soft drinks. He wants--
- No, no, no, no.
- [Nestor] What?
There's a fight at Miss Cita's house!
Huh?
Then, Sir Noel is beating Karla!
- Let's go!
- [Nestor] Huh?!
- [panicking]
- Here, a stick!
- Here it is. Okay.
- [sobs]
- Leave!
Get out of here!
- [Noel] Leave--
- [clamoring]
- [Noel] Leave!
Leave Cita alone!
[in English] That's violence
against women!
- Don't meddle!
- [Cita sobs]
- Don't meddle.
- Go get him!
Leave!
- Arrest him!
- Don't meddle!
[clamoring]
- [clamoring]
- Get out of here!
- Come with us!
What?!
[sobbing]
Sit down first.
Are you okay, child?
[sobbing]
What happened to Janine isn't my fault.
She took Sister Tonet's bag charm,
then threw it.
Then she suddenly disappeared.
[melancholic music playing]
[Atoy] Okay.
Why are you crying?
Because… [sobs]
Maybe you'll be mad at me.
[sobs]
I didn't want Janine
to get into an accident.
Even if we fight,
I don't want her harmed, because…
[sobs] you love her too.
[sighs]
Let's go.
Aunt Audrey.
Are you mad at me?
No, Ibyang.
Atoy, your child is looking for you.
I'll just bring her back to the resort.
The staff who brought her
earlier already left.
She can wait here.
She can't stay here.
She's not allowed here.
- I'll be quick--
- Atoy, what's wrong with you?!
Your daughter is looking for you!
She's not your child!
[intense music playing]
[in English] I'm--
I'm so-- I'm so sorry, Ibyang.
I-I didn't mean it.
[Ibyang] It's true.
[sobs]
I'm not really your child.
Ibyang…
Um, just wait for me there, okay?
Just wait for me.
All right.
What was that?
Why did you say that?
Why are you talking like that
in front of her?
I didn't mean it.
[in English] I have nothing
against Ibyang.
But I'm frustrated with you!
You tell me you want
our family to be whole,
but you prioritize
another child over your own!
What other child? She's not another child.
Ibyang is my responsibility.
I promised her I would take care of her.
But what Janine wants
is just the three of us as a family.
Look. I really do like Ibyang,
but when the two are together,
it's always a disaster!
[in English] They bring out the worst
in each other, Atoy.
They really don't get along!
No, it's just for now! They're kids.
Look, when they grow up, they'll mature.
They'll just laugh
about what they're doing now.
[Audrey] No!
[in English] It'll only get worse.
You have to understand.
Janine grew up in an orphanage,
where she carried
the feeling of being rejected.
That's why she ended up there.
Then, the first one who adopted her
didn't love her either.
So, I understand
why she doesn't want to share us.
Because as long as Ibyang is here,
she'll always feel
she'll never be enough for us.
Atoy, this isn't a shallow insecurity
that will just disappear
when she grows up.
This is a deep wound she still carries.
[melodramatic music playing]
So, what do you want me to do now?
You must choose.
[music fades]
Your child or Ibyang?
Son of--
Don't-- Don't make me do that.
You're unbelievable.
[in English] I'm sorry.
But you can only have one child.
Janine…
or Ibyang.
This is crazy.
Good thing we arrived
before this became a crime scene.
[Fely] Hey, Cita!
Have your husband Noel jailed!
- What he did to you was too much.
- [sobs]
Thank you for coming.
[sobbing]
Are you sure you're okay?
[sobs] Just go back to the shop, Ame.
No one's there.
Um, okay.
Just let me know
if you need anything, okay.
[melancholic music playing]
Take care, both of you.
- Mm, thank you.
- Take care.
Cita, Noel is at the barangay.
You can go face each other to file a case.
I'll be back.
Stay here, okay.
[sobbing]
- Cita, let's go now.
- [sobs]
I'll be back.
- [sobbing]
- [melodramatic music playing]
[Audrey] You must choose.
Your child or Ibyang.
[melodramatic music playing]
[Ibyang] Thank you, Tatoy.
Why?
[somber music playing]
Because…
you're still here for me.
Sorry if…
you and Aunt Audrey fought because of me.
[sighs]
Don't worry about that.
That's how it is. Sometimes…
you have to fight over big things,
for everyone's good.
[gentle music playing]
I just believe in you.
I know you didn't do anything wrong.
Come on. I'll take you home.
[sentimental music playing]
[electronic blipping]
Are you crying?
Your daddy is sending Ibyang home.
[Audrey] We want you to feel
that your daddy
and I love you very much, child.
Delfin knows you're his youngest.
[Karla] What about Brother Atoy?
Did he just accept everything?
He doesn't know.
Brother Atoy is so kind to us.
He needs to know the truth.
‪UP NEXT
- Come on, come on.
- Let's go, let's go.
I wish…
[sobs]
I was really your child.
[Ibyang] So you wouldn't give me away.
[sobs]
You're the only Tatoy I have.
["Mr. Tailor" playing]
[sobs]
♪ Oh, Mr. Tailor ♪
♪ Holding the scissors ♪
♪ One cut, and it's settled ♪
♪ Fix it ♪
Subtitle translation by: Rachel C. Arias